## Ramón Morcillo

Senior Full Stack Engineer, CTO, Founder, and Mentor | Expert in Cloud Architecture & Agile Methodologies for startups | Driving Innovation in Coliving Spaces

hey@ramonmorcillo.com
ramonmorcillo.com
LinkedIn
Live version

Problem solver and experienced maker with a passion for excellence and pragmatism. I create captivating software experiences that bring joy to people's lives. I also guide individuals and teams through personalized coaching and mentoring services.

#### **Skills**

**Front-End:** React, Next.js, Tailwind, Zod, Chakra, Storybook, Jest, Cypress, tRPC, React Query **Back-End:** Node.js, GraphQL, tRPC, serverless, Prisma, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Al, AWS, Azure,

Docker, Kubernetes

Soft: Strong communication, Documentation, Asking Questions, Transparency, Open minded

#### **Work Experience**

# Senior Full Stack Engineer Coral Innovation GmbH

Dec 2023 - Present

- Led team improvements, making us work smarter and get better together.
- Made our coding 30% faster and more efficient by setting up coding standards, guidelines, and documentation.
- Implemented and refined key features in the product with a high standard for code quality and serving as a model for best coding practices.

#### Head of Engineering Human Does

Feb 2024 - Present

- Simplifying digital complexities for businesses by handling everything from social media setups to web development.
- Developing user-centric websites and applications that engage and convert visitors, increasing conversion rates by 25%.
- Implementing tailored digital marketing strategies that boost visibility and engagement, leading to a 30% increase in online traffic.
- Offering a personalized touch by diving deep into clients' businesses and providing strategies that align with their brand and goals.

- Building the first booking engine for coliving spaces.
- Helping coliving spaces to save up to 30% in commissions.
- Increasing the occupancy rate of coliving spaces by 20%.

#### Senior Full Stack Engineer Mapmelon

Nov 2022 - Present

- Improve the lives of Digital Nomads and Remote Workers connecting over 10,000 users to authentic community-focused coliving spaces.
- Developed the platform from scratch, leading to a 40% increase in user engagement within the first 6 months.
- Engineered scalable architecture, ensuring 99.9% uptime and accommodating a 30% quarterly growth in traffic.

# Mentor & Coach Mentorship & Coaching

Jan 2024 - Present

- Providing personalized coaching and mentorship services for individuals and teams.
- Specializing in career development, technical skills enhancement, and leadership training.
- Empowering clients to achieve their professional goals through structured guidance and support.

# Senior Full Stack Engineer On Target Al

Jun 2023 - Dec 2023

- Crafted user interfaces that improved user experience scores by 35%.
- Implemented a scalable codebase, reducing bug reports by 50%.

# Full Stack Engineer Flick

Nov 2021 - Jun 2023

- Integrated an Al Social Marketing Assistant, increasing user retention by 25%.
- Expanded platform to new social channels, contributing to a 30% growth in user base.

## Full Stack Engineer One Beyond

March 2020 - Nov 2021

### One Beyond

- Designed a reusable ecommerce platform, leading to a 50% increase in client acquisition.
- Enhanced rich interfaces, enhancing customer satisfaction by 30%.
- Orchestrated K8s microservice clusters, reducing deployment times by 40%.
- Managed and Terraformed Azure Cloud infrastructure, cutting operational costs by 20%.

#### Full Stack Engineer 1millionbot

Jan 2017 - March 2020

- Enhanced the company dashboard, speeding up chatbot training by 50%.
- Streamlined company's architecture integration into GCP, resulting in a 35% improvement in system reliability.

## **Project Highlights (see more)**

Mapmelon 2022 - Present

The all-in-one app for nomad colivers. Discover, Connect, and Share with the Coliving Community.

BuildPublic 2023

Manage your social presence as a maker, with Al-powered build updates.

How to Live 2021

A collection of life advices learned along the way.

## **Education and languages**

Degree in Software Engineering - Alicante University, 2013 Master in Web Engineering - Madrid Polytechnic University, 2019

I speak and write <a> Spanish (native)</a>, <a> English (fluent)</a>

## What others say about me

Check what others say about me in the resume live version